[{"id": "59d185103b17032616b590fc", "question": "What century poem contains the earliest reference to Robin Hood?", "answer": "1370", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe3ee068b5801b8f54a7fb6", "question": "The ancient Romans used the word \"mala\" to refer to what food?", "answer": "Apples", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c930", "question": "What is made up of the duodenum, jejenum and ileum?", "answer": "Small intestine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa5b", "question": "Port Vila is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Vanuatu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7f9", "question": "What is a second full moon in a month called?", "answer": "Blue moon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c73b", "question": "What psychiatrist developed the principal of \"synchronicity\"?", "answer": "Carl Jung", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f7464a9e54d890926f6f6", "question": "How many steps must visitors take to reach the site of two Buddhist temples in China called Fanjingshan?", "answer": "8,888", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef6", "question": "What horror movie was based on the novel \"Ratman's Notebooks\"?", "answer": "Willard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4b59a06d333868d34d6ea", "question": "Which country's troops withdrew from the Lebanese security zone after 22 years of occupation in 2000?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339947", "question": "Before becoming James Bond, Pierce Brosnan starred for five years on what TV series?", "answer": "Remington Steele", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339048", "question": "Which Tennesee Williams play is about a Italian-American woman?", "answer": "The Rose Tattoo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c311", "question": "What element are diamonds made of?", "answer": "Carbon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b86e", "question": "What is the point value of the outer bull's eye on the dartboard?", "answer": "25 points", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c845", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the sclera?", "answer": "The eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a26d", "question": "McLean Stevenson played which character in the TV series \"M*A*S*H\"?", "answer": "Lt. Colonel Henry Blake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b39", "question": "What Clint Eastwood film was loosely inspired by the 1960's serial killer known as the Zodiac Killer?", "answer": "Dirty Harry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbaf", "question": "In karate, what color belt is earned just before black?", "answer": "Brown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fbae45a0738315b1fb74e1e", "question": "Who scored the first goal at original Wembley Stadium?", "answer": "David Jack", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c937", "question": "Which is a small flightless bird, also New Zealand's national symbol?", "answer": "Kiwi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa94", "question": "What is the capital of the Canadian province Nova Scotia?", "answer": "Halifax", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c040", "question": "What is a group of Oxen called?", "answer": "Yoke", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac79", "question": "During which American period did stock car racing gain most of its popularity?", "answer": "The Prohibition", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede1eb6ce05a3942286dc8", "question": "In \"Frosty the Snowman\", what are Frosty's eyes made of?", "answer": "Coal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a219", "question": "Who was the first winner of the UK \"Big Brother\"?", "answer": "Craig Phillips", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b6b1e662d71a5365100c", "question": "What is the name of the vampire hunter and animator in Laurell K. Hamilton's \"The Harlequin\"?", "answer": "Anita Blake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6691ea5bfecdd737e0877", "question": "What is the main alcohol in a Moscow Mule?", "answer": "Vodka", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51529ff04d658268c92e8", "question": "What war ended with the Battle of Worcester on 3 September 1651?", "answer": "The\u00a0English Civil War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7aa", "question": "Who created the Tabasco sauce?", "answer": "Edmund McIlhenny", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a91f", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Shafter?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af50", "question": "What happened on September 1, 1939 that led to Britain and France declaring war on Germany?", "answer": "Invasion of Poland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af45", "question": "What was the first American space station to be launched into space?", "answer": "Skylab", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f22", "question": "What TV show closes with a logo for \"30th Century Fox\"?", "answer": "Futurama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa97", "question": "What ocean does the Zambezi River empty into?", "answer": "Indian ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "590681a8ff9c0647b50a8096", "question": "What is the name of Beyonce\u2019s sixth studio album, released in April 2016?", "answer": "Lemonade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a20f", "question": "Jason Voorhees first appeared in the nightmare of which \"Friday the 13th\" character?", "answer": "Alice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5e7b6ce05a3942286e34", "question": "Whose 2018 LP is titled \"Beautiful People Will Ruin Your Life\"?", "answer": "The Wombats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c9", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \"I've said it before and I'll say it again: Democracy simply doesn't work.\"?", "answer": "Kent Brockman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7689deec85e375820b2a3", "question": "Which US state has the most national parks?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d4042596a59cbdfbd3a0", "question": "What do websites use to remember your preferences?", "answer": "Cookies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b17445bbb2d29f81593b6fa", "question": "Who wrote and starred in the 1922 version of the film \"Robin Hood\"?", "answer": "Douglas Fairbanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f3057145aa2bc17b61b2ace", "question": "What US Navy rank is indicated by three equal stripes?", "answer": "Commander", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed1", "question": "What reality show gave America the catchphrase \"That's hot\"?", "answer": "The Simple Life", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe771d1eec85e375820b300", "question": "Which country hosts the world's highest marathon?", "answer": "Nepal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399de", "question": "Who was the only one of the six main characters on \"Friends\" to not get married at any time on the show?", "answer": "Joey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5de655bcf89b9ec3da2d335a", "question": "What auto engine part uses exhaust gas energy to pressurize the intake air?", "answer": "Turbocharger", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f7", "question": "What was the first name of the cartoon character Mr. Magoo?", "answer": "Quincy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d118bc4fea7fe947a22287", "question": "How many successive Wimbledon titles did Bjorn Borg win?", "answer": "5", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f6", "question": "What Beatles song begins with the opening fanfare from the French national anthem?", "answer": "All You Need is Love", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b6b", "question": "What future Oscar-winning actress played the title role on the 1960's sitcom \"Gidget\"?", "answer": "Sally Field", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac2f", "question": "Who was the first U.S. billionaire?", "answer": "John D. Rockerfeller", "category": "history"}, {"id": "596dffd39616e6c6d4eba500", "question": "The Spanish Civil War began in what year? ", "answer": "1936", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aae7", "question": "Accra is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Ghana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe769e3eec85e375820b2b3", "question": "An archipelago of 169 Pacific islands known as the \"Friendly Islands\", Tonga has what capital city?", "answer": "Nuk'alofa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c77ce8924f0f7a362efd547", "question": "Who was Sherlock Holmes\u2019s assistant?", "answer": "Dr. Watson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d2d", "question": "What movie was partially inspired by Jean Shepherd's unpublished story \"Flick's Tongue\"?", "answer": "A Christmas Story", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51342ff04d658268c92d7", "question": "What was the goal of the Marshall Plan?", "answer": "Rebuild war-devastated regions, remove trade barriers, modernize industry, and prevent the spread of communism.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ae", "question": "Who received a patent for the first electric razor in 1930?", "answer": "Jacob Schick", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58bb33cde368446ca7bd6848", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Taming of the Shrew\", what is the name of the shrew?", "answer": "Katherina", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c203", "question": "Which country were the 1900 Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3d", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"In the Drain\"?", "answer": "Stuart Little", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a4", "question": "What baseball team was known as the \"Gashouse Gang\"?", "answer": "The St. Louis Cardinals", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60173d2b44491cbd7c5a17aa", "question": "What is the oldest active international airline?", "answer": "KLM Royal Dutch Airlines -- Founded in 1919, KLM is also the\u00a0oldest airline in the world\u00a0still operating under its original name.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a7", "question": "What baseball player was nicknamed \"Joltin' Joe\" and the \"Yankee Clipper\"?", "answer": "Joe DiMaggio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b4", "question": "Canadian Prime Minister Lester Pearson won the Nobel Peace Prize for defusing what world crisis?", "answer": "The Suez Crisis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c944", "question": "Who invented the kinetoscope?", "answer": "Louis Le Prince", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff2152b31a458464a93c45d", "question": "The \"pomsky\" dog breed is a mix between which two dogs?", "answer": "Siberian Husky and Pomeranian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b1", "question": "In \"Bart vs. Australia,\" Homer threatened the members of Parliament with what?", "answer": "A big boot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b36d01dd7bf43be5e7af", "question": "A clowder is a name given to a group of what?", "answer": "Domestic cats", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b0e98e964118b2bb3809cc", "question": "On what day in February was the 2010 romantic comedy film \"Valentine\u2019s Day\" released?", "answer": "February 10", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0db34fcbed638185eaa08", "question": "Where is the only tropical botanical garden listed on UNESCO's World Heritage Site list?", "answer": "Singapore", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6010c9be0775fa611bce67ef", "question": "McDonald\u2019s restaurant periodically runs a themed promotion based on what board game?", "answer": "Monopoly -- Since 1987, McDonald's customers have been hoping to win prizes using game pieces off their soda cups and fries.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff7bfec2b316f4693fb6796", "question": "Where is the goat-racing capital of the world?", "answer": "Tobago", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b0", "question": "What is the name of the coffee shop the \"Friends\" gang frequents?", "answer": "Central Perk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a09b", "question": "What was the first Mickey Mouse cartoon?", "answer": "Plane Crazy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133987f", "question": "In Star Wars, what is the name of Han Solo's ship?", "answer": "The Millenium Falcon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339912", "question": "Versacorp and Protege were the names of the two teams on the first season of what reality show?", "answer": "The Apprentice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25f2066682715b82711ce6", "question": "Feijoada is the national dish of which South American country?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a558", "question": "What is the capital of Washington?", "answer": "Olympia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb58", "question": "How many years are in a semicentennial?", "answer": "50", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd66092a5bfecdd737e0835", "question": "How many Earths could fit in the Sun?", "answer": "1.3 million", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594d06d21a1c922dd1ac64b0", "question": "What is the oldest bridge over the river Seine in Paris?", "answer": "Pont Neuf", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abbd", "question": "Where might you drink Retsina wine?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6aa", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for the element Magnesium on the periodic table?", "answer": "Mg", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e046fe83fe1f2a824b89", "question": "What U.S. President refused to use the telephone while in office?", "answer": "Calvin Coolidge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339beb", "question": "What year saw the debut of the TV show \"Wheel of Fortune\"?", "answer": "1975", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3bb", "question": "Which Renaissance City was severely flooded in November 1966?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba6", "question": "What is the capital of Wyoming?", "answer": "Cheyenne", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339841", "question": "What was the first movie to feature Al Pacino and Robert DeNiro on screen together?", "answer": "Heat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338afe", "question": "Which character killed Richard Cory?", "answer": "Himself", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2dd", "question": "What is the fastest flying butterfly?", "answer": "Skipper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb3b", "question": "What are the three yellow properties on the standards Monopoly board?", "answer": "Marvin Gardens, Atlantic Avenue and Ventnor Avenue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bada", "question": "What brand of cat food was advertised by Morris the Cat?", "answer": "9 Lives", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e14", "question": "George Orwell's \"Animal Farm\" is a roman \u00e0 clef for what historical event?", "answer": "The Russian Revolution", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe76f73eec85e375820b2ea", "question": "What is the only walled city north of Mexico?", "answer": "Quebec City, Quebec, Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b8", "question": "Which British rock group released a debut album called \"Parachutes\"?", "answer": "Coldplay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a294", "question": "What band eventually evolved into the Bee Gees?", "answer": "The Rattlesnakes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be89", "question": "What type of a tree killed Jackson Pollock?", "answer": "Oak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c5c50775fa611bce67cb", "question": "Turmeric is a popular spice that is used in Asian dishes.  What other use does it have?", "answer": "Turmeric is also a powerful anti-inflammatory often used in traditional medicine.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba83", "question": "Where did Saints quarterback Drew Brees play college football?", "answer": "Purdue University", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339713", "question": "How many Oscars did the movie \"American Beauty\" win?", "answer": "5", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcdd", "question": "In chess notation, what move is indicated by \"O-O\"?", "answer": "Castling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a565", "question": "Which US state is home to the Pebble Beach Golf Links?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b834", "question": "How many times are Mexican refried beans fried?", "answer": "Once", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597dddfb77980686f722d17e", "question": "Which century saw the appearance of playing cards?", "answer": "9th Century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a6", "question": "What color is the supposedly cursed Hope Diamond?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339641", "question": "What is the name of Thor's hammer?", "answer": "Mjolnir", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339019", "question": "In what literary work would you find the Yahoos?", "answer": "Gulliver's Travels", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c45d", "question": "A spider typically has eight legs and eight what?", "answer": "Eyes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c41a", "question": "What ancient creature took its name from the Greek words for \"terrible lizard\"?", "answer": "Dinosaur", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe530031bf59ab7d2e38118", "question": "How many states does the Hoover Dam power?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5922067da4edfd43a087adee", "question": "In which Arthur Miller play does Willy Loman feature?", "answer": "Death of a Salesman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ab0fd0baab681b0929216a", "question": "Valentine's Day is also known as the \"Feast of...\" what?", "answer": "Saint Valentine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3dc4ff048f679a45ab52", "question": "What bird is also known as the South American ostrich?", "answer": "Rhea", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b5", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the three-eyed fish named?", "answer": "Blinky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a397", "question": "What is \"The Windy City\"?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396f3", "question": "What was John Wayne\u2019s nickname?", "answer": "The Duke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339941", "question": "Who had Top 10 hits in the 1950\u2019s with \"Ain\u2019t That a Shame\" and \"Blueberry Hill\"?", "answer": "Fats Domino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d117cb4fea7fe947a2227c", "question": "Which German firm produced the World War II plane known as the Condor?", "answer": "Focke-Wulf", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a0", "question": "What is Demeter the goddess of?", "answer": "Harvest and agriculture", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff8", "question": "Who plays the title character in the 1955 musical \"Daddy Long Legs\"?", "answer": "Fred Astaire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0db", "question": "Who composed the music for the opera \"The Tales of Hoffman\"?", "answer": "Jacques Offenbach", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6018bd8bd96d05b23b28165c", "question": "Atropos, Lachesis, and Clotho are the Three what of Greek mythology?", "answer": "Fates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac15", "question": "The Union of the Comoros is located on the northern end of which water channel?", "answer": "Mozambique Channel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb650f5dad637d903c8833", "question": "What African ethnic group is known as \"the people of the veil\" because the men wear veils that conceal all but their eyes?", "answer": "Tuareg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febb2d37e83c707845b2114", "question": "HIV stands for what?", "answer": "Human Immunodeficiency Virus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6f6", "question": "In what body of water can one find the Dry Tortugas islands?", "answer": "Gulf of Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b914", "question": "What popular toy was invented by taking empty pie plates are throwing them in the air?", "answer": "Frisbee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef65486ce05a3942286e6b", "question": "Who directed the film \"The Usual Suspects\"?", "answer": "Bryan Singer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c368", "question": "What acid gives citrus fruits their distinctive sharp flavor?", "answer": "Citric acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa29", "question": "In what Indian city is the Taj Mahal located?", "answer": "Agra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339124", "question": "Jean de Brunhoff created the appearance of Babar the Elephant, but who invented the character?", "answer": "Cecile de Brunhoff", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b44d", "question": "What world leader was assassinated in Cairo on October 6, 1981?", "answer": "Anwar Sadat", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b22d", "question": "Who christened Hawaii \"the Sandwich Islands\" in 1778?", "answer": "Captain Cook", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7b5", "question": "What do the letters X.O. stand for on a bottle of cognac?", "answer": "Extra Old", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76840eec85e375820b29e", "question": "Which U.S. city is referred to as \"The Hub of the Universe\"?", "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f0f", "question": "What author created the character of Dr. Gideon Fell?", "answer": "John Dickson Carr", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac06", "question": "What was the Republic of Nauru previously known as?", "answer": "Pleasant Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bcf", "question": "In Norse mythology who are the female attendants of Odin?", "answer": "The Valkyrie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad0f", "question": "What continent borders the Weddell Sea?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e5f116ed274615ecf514539", "question": "What is the name of Olive Oyl\u2019s sister-in-law?", "answer": "Cylinda Oyl", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b4", "question": "In Greek mythology what is the place of ideal happiness called?", "answer": "Elysium", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c1", "question": "What is the name of Squire Trelawney's ship in \"Treasure Island\"?", "answer": "Hispaniola", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5afad8bb430e050a5df0d113", "question": "How many hearts does an Octopus have?", "answer": "3", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa2a", "question": "In what Australian state would you find Whyalla?", "answer": "South Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd05", "question": "After his death in a 1998 skiing accident, what famous song title was placed on Sonny Bono's headstone?", "answer": "The Beat Goes On", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ea", "question": "In which country was the Michelin tire company founded in 1889?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9af", "question": "What American fashion designer founded the Polo clothing line?", "answer": "Ralph Lauren", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aff7", "question": "What New York building, completed in 1931, was at the time the world's tallest?", "answer": "Empire State Building", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cac6", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for tin?", "answer": "Sn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5901d967709c1c34536e6eab", "question": "What does sonography use to make pictures of the inside of the body?", "answer": "Sound waves", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a1", "question": "How does James Bond like his martinis?", "answer": "Shaken, not stirred", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe93daf6bd93ce3a4e5f6b8", "question": "What astronomical model positioned the Sun near the center of the Universe?", "answer": "Copernican model", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601370831381754895396382", "question": "In the 1990 film \"Home Alone\", the fictitious film that Kevin watches, \"Angels with Filthy Souls\", is a homage to what real film?", "answer": "\"Angels with Dirty Faces\" -- It is a 1938 gangster film starring James Cagney and Pat O'Brien.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b74f", "question": "How many tiles does each player pick at the start of a game of Scrabble?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6018bdeed96d05b23b28165f", "question": "Who was the first person to suggest Daylight Savings Times?", "answer": "British-born, New Zealand entomologist and astronomer George Vernon Hudson is credited with the concept of daylight savings time.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc1", "question": "What is divided by the Cassini Division?", "answer": "Saturn's rings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a52e", "question": "What Ivy League school is located in Ithaca?", "answer": "Cornell University", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b915", "question": "What breakfast favorite, with a hole in the middle, is equal to 4 slices of bread?", "answer": "A bagel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa3eb2c73aa70ea0b70af9", "question": "What was an alternative name for Maryland?", "answer": "Mariana (Lord Baltimore squashed the idea because the name reminded him of Spanish Jesuit and historian Juan de Mariana.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdffc5e1cf6db9ac4808cfd", "question": "What U.S. city's airport code is MCO?", "answer": "Orlando, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b71c", "question": "In what country does Santa typically sport a long coat and beard?", "answer": "England", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a1e1dd9b5a031299b74573e", "question": "What century did the Icelandic Vikings first reach the island of Newfoundland?", "answer": "11th Century", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa6b", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of North Carolina?", "answer": "Raleigh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb24", "question": "What soft drink called itself \"The Un-Cola\"?", "answer": "7-Up", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4de6206d333868d34d714", "question": "Who is known for running through the streets crying Eureka?", "answer": "Archimedes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59c1cdad7bd84c0ea43ad42c", "question": "Which country borders Macedonia to the south?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6989820565ad31a57c735", "question": "Odysseus was the king of what island in the Mediterranean Sea?", "answer": "Ithaca", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600241ac4be4723ccac2217b", "question": "Which book by Thomas More, published in 1516, depicts an ideal fictional island society?", "answer": "\"Utopia\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe0e306fcbed638185eaa1f", "question": "Where is the United Nations (UN) Headquarters located?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921d", "question": "In which movie does Hugh Grant play a London bookshop owner?", "answer": "Notting Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590681c6ff9c0647b50a8097", "question": "Under what name did Nintendo re-release the Nintendo Entertainment System in 2016?", "answer": "Nintendo Entertainment System: NES Classic Edition", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339991", "question": "In the movie \"Ferris Bueller\u2019s Day Off\", what was Ferris\u2019 girlfriend\u2019s first name?", "answer": "Sloan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25aa1b63e5727cf5a4855", "question": "Which song was featured in the 1991 film \"Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves\" and held the number one spot in the UK singles chart for 16 weeks?", "answer": "(Everything I Do) I Do It for You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339221", "question": "Which two artists formed the band \"Wham!\"?", "answer": "George Michael and Andrew Ridgeley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ecb", "question": "What French word for \"jewel\" became a common name for American movie houses?", "answer": "Bijou", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a634", "question": "What city is home to the University of Oregon?", "answer": "Eugene", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c673", "question": "Jonas Salk discovered a vaccine for what disease?", "answer": "Polio", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af256d4b63e5727cf5a4840", "question": "What movie franchise action figures did Kenner start producing in the 1970s that led to its success and the popularization of the 3.75 inch action figure?", "answer": "Star Wars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f60", "question": "Which 1966 story, by Philip K. Dick, served as the basis for the 1990 movie \"Total Recall\"?", "answer": "We Can Remember It for You Wholesale", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6656ca5bfecdd737e085f", "question": "What three vows do Catholic priests take?", "answer": "Poverty, chastity and obedience", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133915a", "question": "Who is Bugs Bunny's archenemy?", "answer": "Elmer J. Fudd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f025cee580c7f8fd1e4a", "question": "What famous general was nicknamed \"Old blood and guts\" by his men?", "answer": "General George S. Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af0f", "question": "What did American patriots dump into Boston Harbor in 1773 to protest British import taxes?", "answer": "Tea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fbf", "question": "What genre is Neil Young considered to be the grandfather of?", "answer": "Grunge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c83", "question": "In 2001, who gave the first concert in Oslo's Vallhall football arena?", "answer": "A-ha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b573", "question": "What sport is Jenson Button associated with?", "answer": "Motorsport", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339888", "question": "What colour was Oscar the Grouch during the first season of Sesame Street?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010ca1f0775fa611bce67f3", "question": "What Apple computer was named after Steve Jobs' daughter?", "answer": "Lisa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59637204967692ea851899bc", "question": "Ford produced the Model T in only what color after 1913?", "answer": "Black", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a419", "question": "What Scottish landmark borders on Fort Augustus?", "answer": "Loch Ness", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339caa", "question": "What hero of 1926 played herself in the 1927 film \"Swim, Girl, Swim\"?", "answer": "Gertrude Ederle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133910e", "question": "What current-day country was writer, neurologist and psychiatrist Viktor Frankl born in?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede34d6ce05a3942286dd1", "question": "Who was originally cast as Holly Golightly in \"Breakfast at Tiffany\u2019s\"?", "answer": "Marilyn Monroe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a899c2e60d398dc9cf7a6a5", "question": "Vesta is the Roman goddess of what?", "answer": "Hearth, home and family", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b21", "question": "Stings first solo album was entitled \"The Dream of the Blue...\" what?", "answer": "Turtles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5922028ca4edfd43a087addf", "question": "How many strings are there on the \"Spanish Guitar\"?", "answer": "Six", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b93a", "question": "What type of athlete is also called a powder puff, tanker, catcher or knuckle duster?", "answer": "A boxer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c392", "question": "What method of food preservation was invented for the British Navy in 1813?", "answer": "Canning", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea788fff048f679a45abdb", "question": "What is a \"Haricot Vert\"?", "answer": "A tender string bean", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb57", "question": "What British entrepreneur sold his Virgin Music Group to Thorn EMI in 1992?", "answer": "Richard Branson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c15c", "question": "At which sport was Hungarian Victor Barna World Champion 5 times?", "answer": "Table Tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad9", "question": "Who created the \"Spy vs Spy\" silent comic strip?", "answer": "Antonio Prohias", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9fd", "question": "What do scientists call the \u201cbelt\u201d that is orbiting the sun between Mars and Jupiter?", "answer": "Asteroid Belt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5921fff1a4edfd43a087add5", "question": "Whose painting \"Irises\" was sold to Alan Bond in 1987?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391af", "question": "Who dramatically kissed Halle Berry on stage when he won Best Actor?", "answer": "Adrien Brody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff14066b0ee8c595b6d399c", "question": "Which 1920s play is the first major play written for children?", "answer": "\"Peter Pan\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339584", "question": "Who directed the 1968 movie \"Night of the Living Dead\"?", "answer": "George A. Romero", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a19f", "question": "Who is Homer Simpson's half-brother?", "answer": "Herb Powell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d59", "question": "What famed TV personality wrote the screenplay for 1968's \"Planet of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Rod Sterling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5adc6ce05a3942286e0e", "question": "Which team did John Madden, of \"Madden NFL\" fame, win a Super Bowl with as head coach?", "answer": "Oakland Raiders", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601de9f76b1208747aa7e9d5", "question": "In the Chinese zodiac, with which of the five elements is the snake associated?", "answer": "Fire -- It points to aggression and dominance.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e6", "question": "What was the first NASA program to land an object on Mars that sent information back to Earth?", "answer": "Viking", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a010", "question": "What TV show's famed \"puffy shirt\" is in the Smithsonian today?", "answer": "Seinfeld's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e7", "question": "What is the longest one syllable word in the English language?", "answer": "Screeched", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce7", "question": "What is Mr. Snuffleupagus's given name?", "answer": "Aloysius", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf0", "question": "What is the condition resulting from prolonged muscular or mental activity?", "answer": "Fatigue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0aebde662d71a53650fbb", "question": "What was Bram Stoker's original name for Dracula?", "answer": "Count Wampyr", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b74e", "question": "What is the highest number on a standard roulette wheel?", "answer": "36", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c87c", "question": "What chemical element has an extra syllable in its more correct British pronunciation?", "answer": "Aluminium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b3589ac5db0d66a186cb54d", "question": "Until 1989, what European country was the world\u2019s second largest exporter of bottled wine?", "answer": "Bulgaria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaed", "question": "Dodoma is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Tanzania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969c", "question": "Who played Jason's love interest in the 2002 movie \"The Bourne Identity\"?", "answer": "Franka Potente", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3a1cc73aa70ea0b70add", "question": "Toronto is on the shores of which Great Lake?", "answer": "Ontario", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c29f", "question": "The Richter scale measures what?", "answer": "The strength of earthquakes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d1", "question": "Which author built a home called Goldeneye in Jamaica?", "answer": "Ian Fleming", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a876", "question": "In what city would you find \"Peachtree Street\"?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ae", "question": "What is the capitol of Morocco?", "answer": "Rabat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a1a31a12f2a7826b9b8722", "question": "What is ornamental work in silver or gold thread or beads called?", "answer": "Filigree", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a65", "question": "What 1973 movie sparked the careers of Harrison Ford, Richard Dreyfuss, Mackenzie Phillips, and Cindy Williams?", "answer": "American Graffiti", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a83b", "question": "Albania, Bulgaria, Greece, Bosnia and Herzegovia, Kosovo, and a few other countries make up what peninsula?", "answer": "Balkan peninsula", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3d5dff048f679a45ab4b", "question": "What is the tendency of Earth's rotation to turn winds called?", "answer": "Coriolis Effect", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baac", "question": "What newspaper, founded in 1801, has been well known for its gossip column called \"Page Six\"?", "answer": "New York Post", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf7e", "question": "What does WD stand for in WD 40?", "answer": "Water Displacement", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c65c", "question": "What keeps the Earth's atmosphere from leaving the planet?", "answer": "Gravity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf14", "question": "Who rode Shergar to victory in the Epsom Derby?", "answer": "Walter Swinburn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d1", "question": "What is the capital of New Mexico?", "answer": "Santa Fe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1b4", "question": "By what nickname was boxer John L. Sullivan also known as?", "answer": "The Boston Strong Boy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e7", "question": "What does a pedometer count?", "answer": "Steps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c576", "question": "Which planet in our solar system is known as the Earth's twin?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab18adbaab681b0929218d", "question": "What country is home to Volvo?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b490049076251badbeaaa", "question": "The Treaty of Ghent was the peace treaty that ended which war?", "answer": "War of 1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed0", "question": "What year did Hawaii become a US state?", "answer": "1959", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339033", "question": "Who wrote the the novel \"The Dam Busters\"?", "answer": "Paul Brickhill", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590089dccf842fa4c4ba968c", "question": "What was the first solo album released by Roger Waters?", "answer": "The Pros and Cons of Hitch Hiking", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae97", "question": "To what tribe did Sitting Bull belong?", "answer": "Sioux", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938f", "question": "What role did James Dean play in the movie \"Rebel Without a Cause\"?", "answer": "Jim Stark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feccd5cec223966ae8f88ab", "question": "What bikini-clad seashell hunter does James Bond meet in \"Dr. No\"?", "answer": "Honey Ryder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990f4d9fa5fdd6dd25324e7", "question": "Central African Republic shares its western border with which country?", "answer": "Cameroon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5901dbe5709c1c34536e6eb3", "question": "With what artist did Kid Rock record the song titled \"Picture\"?", "answer": "Sheryl Crow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b122", "question": "What was the two-word code name for Woodward and Bernstein's secret Watergate source?", "answer": "Deep Throat", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5cb", "question": "The Pathfinder spacecraft landed on what planet in 1997?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af34", "question": "Which treaty ended the war between Germany and the Allied Powers in World War I?", "answer": "Treaty of Versailles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd5", "question": "Farnsworth Bentley became famous for holding whose umbrellas?", "answer": "Puff Daddy's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b948", "question": "What was S.S. Kresge renamed to in 1977?", "answer": "Kmart", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf55", "question": "This drink is made from espresso coffee, hot milk and chocolate?", "answer": "Mocha", "category": "general"}]